# Dhanya Kunhikrishnan

dhanyakunhi@gmail.com | +61 411 287 645 | Perth, WA 6112

Github: https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhankrish/

Portfolio: https://dhanva-krishnan2.github.io/Latest-portfolio-with-music/

#### **SUMMARY**

Bilingual Web Developer and a passionate Software Quality Assurance tester with more than one year of experience in the software development industry having love of computers and continuous learning. Highly innovative when problem-solving and taking on challenges and priorities, the task, always follows the pattern of continuous Integration and deployment. Communication with other team members is a high priority as we share a common passion of creating dynamically engaging applications to bear our human experience in the modern world and also a great mathematician who holds an Engineering degree from Mahatma Gandhi University and Certification in JavaScript BootcampUniversity of Western Australia and Udemy Certification in AWS, Azure technologies.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap • Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize • Adobe Photoshop • Git, Github, Visual Studio Code • Handlebars.js, ORM, MongoDB, React.js, ES6. • Zoom Communications • JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Rest APIs • Team development and Trello • Heroku Deployment • Java • Artificial Intelligence and Computer Networking • Test Cases, Plans & Scripts• System and Acceptance Testing, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Validation Testing, Output Testing , Jest Test framework for React • Software Architecture Technologies • Azure Architecture Certification • Agile project Management • zoho CRM • WordPress

#### **PROJECTS**

**Eco-Meet-ups** | https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2/Lucky-Nine-2/Project-2--Eco-Meet-up | Deployed: https://murmuring-bayou-85480.herokuapp.com/

- The main functionality of this app is to create an event that happening near by place and gathering a group of people to help clean up and that way help the community as a responsible citizen
- This project is a group collaboration of three enthusiastic people.
- My role is to develop the front-end as well as to create client side javascript.
- <u>Tools</u> HTML, JavaScript, Mongodb, Context API, EmailJS, Express js, Node js, Bootstrap, MomentJS

**Covid-19-Hub**| <a href="https://github.com/ong-osmond/Lucky\_Nine">https://github.com/ong-osmond/Lucky\_Nine</a> | <a href="mailto:My Role">My Role</a> | <a href="mailto:Deployed">Deployed</a> | <a href="https://ong-osmond.github.io/Lucky\_Nine/">https://ong-osmond.github.io/Lucky\_Nine/</a> |

- This App development helps people who are quarantined to determine whether they may need to stay back or they can go normally in this pandemic situation.
- This application makes use of an API from Infermedica and works the dynamic questionnaire updating via API.
- Tools HTML, Axios, Bootstrap and CSS, moment js, axios, Infermedica API

**Employee-directory**| <a href="https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2/Employee-directory">https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2/Employee-directory</a>| <a href="https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/">The Demo found at <a href="https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/">https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/</a>|

The Demo found at <a href="https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/">https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/</a>|

The Demo found at <a href="https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/">https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/</a>|

The Demo found at <a href="https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/">https://dhanya-krishnan2.github.io/Employee-directory/</a>|

- This is a <u>React</u> app that lets you view a list of employees, search for a specific employee, and sort the employee by either name or department.
- When you search for an employee it will immediately give you a result and clicking on the buttons will sort the employees either in ascending or descending order
- <u>Tools</u> Node.js and Mongodb, React JS, moment.js, Tailwind.css
   Food-Hub|

https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2/connect-with-food | Deployed | https://damp-sierra-19586.herokuapp.com/ |

- This App development helps people to connect through food and the home contains a sign- up form or a sign in form. After sign-up we will search up for a particular address we can reach and we will get the hotels nearby the place, if nothing available we will get an error message saying no hotels in your searched area.
- If the user is able to see a particular hotel and foods they want they can order the food and add from many hotels and then it will place in the cart and finalise their purchase.
- Here customers can enter as the seller and they need to register with their email address and then add the images and all the details of the food they are going to sell and they are allowed to change the details of the food they entered at any time.
- This application makes use of an google geocode API, Places API etc to achieve the search bar working.
- The front end of the application is made by using React JS, React Redux, React Hooks, and the Styles done mainly by Material UI.
- This is a MERN stack application and the backend is mainly done by using Node JS, Express, and Mongodb, Mongoose.
- The is here done by using JEST framework in the front end and the back end testing is done using Unit Testing

# Google Book Search |

https://github.com/Dhanya-krishnan2/full-stack-application-google-book-search | The Demo found at | https://whispering-atoll-21977.herokuapp.com/

• This is a MERN stack application which is developed to store my favourite book and it will act as a library for the reference.

- Utilizing Google's API & MongoDB, I allow the user to post, delete, and read from the database. I also took advantage of React Hooks to allow for functional based components.
- <u>Tools</u> Node.js and Mongodb, React js, moment.js, Tailwind.css

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Western Australia**, Coding Bootcamp – Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Mahatma Gandhi University, Bachelor of Engineering (Information and Technology)

**Kannur University, Diploma** in Mathematics **TAFE**, Certificate 4 in Education Support **Udemy**, Bootcamp certificate from Udemy

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

**Junior Software Developer** 

Mar 2007 - July 2008

## **Cyber Prism**

Kerala India

- worked in a software company who is responsible for the development of the real-world project using the languages as follows,
- Front-end: J2SEE, JSP, C#, .Net, ASP.Net
- Back-end: SQL Server, Microsoft MS ACCESS.
- The responsibility is to work within a group to achieve a positive outcome of the client requirement. My role involves the test -driven development of software and also includes the polished UI, which impresses the customer.
- I was successful in developing software for online shopping and my part placed an important role to handle the database effectively.
- The testing part includes the system test that makes the assumption that goal will be successfully achieved. A series of testing involved is unit Testing, Integration Testing, Validation Testing, Output Testing, User Acceptance Testing.
- In Unit testing, test each module individually and integrate the overall system, Integration testing uncovers the errors within the interface after combining each module after Unit Testing. In Validation Testing can be passed when the customer reasonably accepts the product.
- Output Testing is the process of checking the output format by linking the customers opinion regarding our product, how the output is displayed normally in two formats one is screen format, the other one is printed format. While these the errors can be found out and corrected and also noted for future use.
- User Acceptance Testing is done with the help of a user by constantly keeping in touch and making changes whenever required.

# OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Teacher-assistant**

2016 - 2020

# **Department of Education**

Perth

- The role here is a place of teamwork which requires to work with a multidisciplinary team including medical-team, Information-technology team and school team.
- Here utilised client relationships, which is a part of a successful role and it includes varieties of people of category.
- As education is the key part of learning the main requisites in the written and verbal communication.

## Full-stack developer

2021 - Present

# Technaus Solar Pty Itd, Armadale, Perth

- This is a Solar energy equipment supplier throughout Australia, My role is developing their business CRM from scratch as well as maintaining their current Zoho crm to get the lead for the business.
- Integrating another company with existing technaus and which lead me to update the
  other company website and main their domain in Cpanel to create leads through it by
  integrating forms created by the Crm to pdf file to increase the sale.
- Also my responsibilities include to help and maintain the UI for the facebook ecommerce which they are running to create more leads.
- Build the relationship with internal and external stakeholders to update the CRM.